SRUTI CHEEDALLA

UX DEVELOPER & DESIGNER



703.203.4025



✓ scheedalla@gmail.com



• https://scheedalla.github.io

PROFILE

UX Developer with experience in Interaction Design and Research - 10+ years working on projects from start to finish.

SKILLS

Development

HTML5, SASS/CSS3, Javascript, React + Redux + Webpack, Angular, AngularJS, Node.js, JQuery, MEAN, Grunt, Gulp, MongoDB, SQL

Design

Interaction Design, Interactive Prototyping, Responsive Design (Web and Mobile), Accessibility

Research

Card Sorting, Heuristic Evaluations, Usability Testing, Surveys, User Interviews

Other

Agile, DevOps

CERTIFICATIONS

NN/G UX Certificate

Professional Scrum with User Experience

CONFERENCES

Starting from Scratch with the MEAN

MONGODB WORLD, NYC / JUN 2015

When Being MEAN is a Good Thing WOMEN IN TECH SUMMIT / MAR 2016

The Washington Post Developer Day ORGANIZER / 2015, 2017, 2018

EDUCATION

M.S. Information Systems GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY / DEC 2010

B.A. History / Minor Mathematics UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA / MAY 2007

EXPERIENCE

Principal UI/UX Designer/Developer

NORTHROP GRUMMAN / JAN 2020 - PRESENT

- Create low and high fidelity prototypes to demonstrate to clients and cross-functional teams
- Research, analyze, and implement Accessibility improvements
- Provide feedback on customer support inquiries
- Create, code, and debug React components
- Conduct testing sessions on prototypes
- Mentor team members on UX and front-end web development
- Conduct learning sessions on Agile, React ecosystem, and UX
- Conduct user research such as interviews and card sorting

Senior Web Developer

THE WASHINGTON POST / APR 2015 - JAN 2020

- Coordinated and worked closely with UX designers and product owners on creating cohesive, responsive designs
- Implemented and maintained brand new, responsive, reusable, performant redesign of existing sign-in web and mobile application w/1 million + users using React, Redux, and Webpack
- Led team on deployment strategy and coordination with other teams for the new web and mobile application
- Integrated formalized code review process for front end developers to provide greater transparency and documentation
- Led and managed team that orchestrated Developer Day 2017 and 2018, an internal conference at The Washington Post
- For paywall, subscription purchases, and newsletter service coded new components in React, AngularJS, and JQuery
- Enhanced customer service and offer management tools using Angular and Webpack

Web Developer

THE WASHINGTON POST / AUG 2011 - APR 2015

Grew from front-end developer to a full stack senior developer with experience building SASS and Javascript frameworks, writing APIs, managing databases, and maintaining AWS infrastructure.

User Interface Design Intern

MIXNET CORP / AUG 2010 - JAN 2011

Led creation of and redesigned front-end user interface for application efileTaxPro to increase usability, consistency and overall effectiveness of program using ASP.NET, XHTML, and CSS.

Web Intern

N.E.W. CUSTOMER SERVICES COMPANY / SUMMER 2010

Debugged and solved front-end issues for the ServiceBench software application, web-based service management solutions for the appliance industry.

Webmaster and Graduate Assistant

HONORS COLLEGE GMU / SEP 2009 - JUL 2010

Developed and maintained websites for the Postgraduate Fellowships and Scholarship, Undergraduate Apprentice programs, and Honors Curriculum.